A Finding Aid to the Erle Loran Papers, 1912-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.loraerle
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1910s-1990s; Series 7; (Boxes 10-12, 14; 2.5 linear feet)
  Photographs of Loran include formal portraits, informal pictures with friends and colleagues, photographs of him at events, and in his studio. Loran's family and spouses are found in family photographs, formal portraits, and informal pictures. Also found are childhood and adolescent photographs of Loran's second wife, Clyta, as well as photographs of her family. There are photographs of Loran's travels in the south of France and the American southwest and Mexico.
  The bulk of the photographs are of Loran's artwork, including exhibitions. Included are photographs of source material and the artwork of others, including Paul Cézanne and Hans Hofmann, and of Loran's own collection of artwork. There are also photographs of Hans Hofmann's visit to Berkeley in 1964.
  This series also includes transparencies, negatives, and slides. Of interest are slides used for a lecture on Cézanne, and one on contemporary art.
  - Erle Loran, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Erle Loran, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Erle Loran, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Erle Loran, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Erle Loran, 1990s (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Clyta Loran, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Clyta Loran, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Clyta Loran, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Clyta and Erle Loran, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Erle Loran With Others, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Erle Loran With Others, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Erle Loran With Others, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Clyta Loran With Others, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Helen Sather, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 10, Folder 50)
    (Loran's first wife)
  - Artwork, 1923-1928 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Artwork, 1931-1939; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Artwork, 1930s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Artwork, circa 1930s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Artwork, 1940-1945; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Artwork, 1946-1947; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Artwork, 1948-1949; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Artwork, 1940s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Artwork, circa 1940s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Artwork, 1950-1954; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Artwork, 1950s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Artwork, circa 1950s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Artwork, 1960-1965 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Artwork, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Artwork, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Artwork, circa 1960s; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 66-68)
  - Artwork, 1971-1980 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Artwork, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Artwork, circa 1970s; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 71-73)
  - Artwork With Sitter, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Artwork With Sitter, circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Artwork With Sitter, circa 1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - African Art, circa 1950s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 14) (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - African Art, 1960s-1970s; (6 folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-12)
  - African Art, 1980s (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Asian Art, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Irish Art, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - South American Art, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Artwork By Others: Paul Cézanne, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 14) (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Artwork By Others: Hans Hofmann, circa 1960s; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - Artwork By Others: Roy Lichtenstein After CézanneDiagrams, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Artwork By Others, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Artwork Installation, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Artwork Installation, circa 1960s-1994 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Artwork Owned By Loran, circa 1970s; (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 24-26)
  - Artwork Owned By Loran, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Aerial Views, circa 1970s-1980s; (12 folders) (Box 11, Folder 28-39)
  - Animals, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Art Class, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Beach, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Canvases, circa 1981 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Cemetery, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Cézanne, circa 1926-1930; (2 folders; see also Box 14) (Box 11, Folder 45-46)
  - Cézanne's Composition, circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Children and Adolescents, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Children and Adolescents, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Commencement Ceremony, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Contact Sheets, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Dancer, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Dory Flodin, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Great Depression, circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Marsden Hartley, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Hans Hofmann, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - House, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 59-61)
  - House, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Loran Family, circa 1910s-1940s; (see also Box 14) (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Loran Family, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Loran Family, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Loran Family, circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 66-67)
  - Models, circa 1960s; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 68-69)
  - Objects, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Party, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Petroglyphs, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Plants, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Professional Activities, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Receptions, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Rural Scenes, circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Sam Sabean, 1944, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Sidhu Family, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Television, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Totem Poles, circa 1971 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Travels, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Travels, circa 1940s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    (from envelope labeled "Stealing Hay")
  - Travels, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Travels, circa 1960s-1970s; (16 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-19)
  - University of California, Berkeley, circa 1940s (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Negatives (Box 12)
    - African Art, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Artwork, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Artwork, circa 1930s-1940s; (6 folders) (Box 12, Folder 23-28)
    - Artwork, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Artwork, circa 1960s; (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 30-32)
    - Artwork, circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Artwork Installation, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Artwork Owned By Loran, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Artwork By Others, circa 1930s-1950s; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 36-37)
    - Cartoons, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Cézanne, circa 1926-1930; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 39-42)
    - Cézanne Diagrams, circa 1940s (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Great Depression, circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - House, circa 1940s-1960s; (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 46-48)
    - Clyta Loran, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Erle Loran, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Erle Loran, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Clyta and Erle Loran, circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Erle Loran With Others, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Loran Family, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Marsden Hartley, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Objects, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Petroglyphs, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - Plants, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Rural Scenes, circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Helen Sather, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - Sitters, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - Travels, circa 1930s-1970s; (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 62-64)
  - Transparencies (Box 12)
    - Artwork Installation, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - African Art, circa 1960s-1970s; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 66-67)
    - Artwork, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Slides (Box 12)
    - Loran: Paintings, 1940s (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Loran: Paintings, 1950s (Box 12)
    - Loran: Paintings, 1950s-1960s (Box 12)
    - Loran: Paintings, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Loran: Paintings, 1960s (Box 12)
    - Loran: Paintings, 1970s (Box 12)
    - Loran: Paintings, 1980s (Box 12)
    - Loran: Watercolors, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 12)
    - Artwork By Others: A-W, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Artwork By Others: Unknown, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Contemporary Art Lecture, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 12)
    - CézanneStill Life Lecture, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Artwork Owned By Loran, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Artwork Installation, circa 1960s (Box 12)
    - Artwork Installation: Others, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Erle Loran, 1960s-1980s (Box 12)
    - Erle and Clyta Loran, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Erle Loran With Others, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 12)
    - African Art, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Asian Art, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Cartoons, 1940s (Box 12)
    - Cézanne's Composition, circa 1943 (Box 12)
    - Computer Art, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Diagrams, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 12)
    - El Greco Motifs in Toledo, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 12)
    - Italian Art, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 12)
    - Museums, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 12)
    - Native American Art, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Navajo Country, 1953 (Box 12)
    - Russian Art, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 12)
  - Artwork, 1932-1948; (see also Box 10) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 10)
  - Artwork, 1940s-1950s; (see also Box 10) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 11)
  - Artwork By Others: Paul Cézanne, circa 1930s-1940s; (see also Box 11) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 12)
  - African Art, circa 1950s; (see also Box 11) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 13)
  - Cézanne, circa 1920s-1930s; (see also Box 11) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 14)
  - Loran Family, 1930s-1940s; (see also Box 11) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 15)
- Audio Recording, 1982; Series 8; (Box 12; 1 folder)
  Found is an audio cassette recording of a lecture by Loran on Cézanne from June 15, 1982.
  - Recording of Lecture by Loran about Cézanne, 1982, June 15; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 12, Folder 73)